Friends , let me introduce myself .
Peltzer 's the name . Rand Peltzer .
That 's me there on the corner .
I 'm an inventor . And I have a story to tell .
Yeah , I know . Who hasn 't got a story ?
Well , nobody 's got a story like this one .
Nobody .
It all started here , in Chinatown .
I was hitting the shops trying to move a little merchandise ,
maybe find a present for my kid .
I tried this one place .
Hey . Wait a minute .
- What 's down here ? - This is it .
- This is your grandfather 's store ? - Yeah .
Come on .
No wonder you gotta drag people in off the street .
Hey , go ahead , mister . Look around .
See if there 's something you like .
Ah .
Are these things real ?
I told you , everything 's real .
Well , friends . You do have a lot of interesting artifacts here ,
but there 's one thing you don 't have .
And what 's that ?
Let me show you . I 've got it right here . I 'm an inventor . I made this .
The Bathroom Buddy .
It 's the invention of the century , friends .
It eliminates the need to carry heavy luggage and things when you travel .
You got yourself your shaving mirror ,
you got yourself your toothbrush , a toothpick . You got toenail clippers ...
You got a nail file ,
and you got yourself a dental mirror .
This is gonna revolutionize traveling .
Now , let 's just say , for the sake of argument ,
that you 're on a bus , a plane or a train .
You forgot to brush your teeth .
You got yourself a bad case of dragon breath .
Bad breath . Now , what do you do ?
No problem , friend . All you do is , you take your toothbrush out ,
and you push this button .
That 's absolutely no problem .
Cleans up easily .
Now , what I 'd like to do , sir , I 'd like to give you my card .
Rand Peltzer . " Fantastic Ideas for a Fantastic World . "
I make the illogical logical .
Now , sir , I can get you these .
I can get them by the dozen if you 'd like .
What do you think ?
Oh .
Where 's that coming from ?
- What is that ? - Mogwai .
- What 's he doing ? - Singing .
He does that sometimes .
I gotta have him . He 's incredible .
Tell you what I 'll do .
- I 'll give you $ 100 for him . - No .
Look , I 've gotta have him . It 's a present for my son for Christmas .
It 's exactly what I 've been looking for .
I 've been everywhere . I 'll give you $ 200 .
That 's $ 200 .
I 'm sorry .
Mogwai not for sale .
I thought you said everything in your grandfather 's store was for sale .
Grandfather !
With mogwai comes much responsibility .
I cannot sell him at any price .
Wait outside . I 'll be right out . Just go .
- Okay , mister , here it is . - Oh , right .
What about your grandfather ?
Forget what he said . He 's crazy . We need the money .
- Now , come on . Do you want it , or not ? - I want it .
Look , mister . There 's three rules you 've gotta follow .
Yeah ? What kind of rules ?
Keep him out of the light .
He hates bright light , especially sunlight .
It 'll kill him .
And keep him away from water . Don 't get him wet .
But the most important rule , the rule you can never forget ...
No matter how much he cries no matter how much he begs ,
never , never feed him after midnight . You got it ?
Sure , kid . Whatever you say .
Hey , listen , thanks . And have a merry Christmas .
Hey , gang . You 're rolling with Rockin ' Ricky Rialto ,
the voice of Kingston Falls , USA !
Simon !
Hey , Alex .
Getting close to Christmas .
Looks like you 're gonna get stuck with a lot of trees again this year .
- I thought I 'd see you about this time . - Huh ?
- Ow ! - What the hell is this ?
Hey . What are you doing in there ?
Don 't ask .
Alex , I came to get my tree .
Pete , take that tree to Mr. Anderson 's truck .
Gee , Dad .
What do you say , Alex ?
Come on . You can spare one for the boys down at the sheriff 's station .
I paid for mine , Frank .
Hey , Billy , what 's the matter ? You need a jump ?
No , thanks , Mr. Futterman . I 'm pretty much late for work as it is .
These goddamn foreign cars , they always freeze up on you .
You don 't find American machinery doing that .
That stuff can take anything .
See that plow ?
Fifteen years old . Hasn 't given me a day 's trouble in 15 years .
You know why ? Kentucky Harvester .
It ain 't some foreign piece of crap you pick up these days .
- That 's a Kentucky Harvester . - Hmm .
If I wanna keep my job , I really think I should be going now .
Hey , how 's that , uh , comic strip of your 's coming ?
I expect to see you in the funnies any day now ,
with Smilin ' Jack and Li 'l Abner .
Oh , Mr. Futterman , they don 't run those comics anymore .
They don 't ?
- Oh . - Come on , Barn .
- Say hello to your wife for me , okay ? - Yeah , sure .
- See you later . - So long , Billy .
Goddamn foreign cars .
Hey , Dr. Murrow .
Morning , Billy . Morning .
- Morning , Tom . - Hey , Billy . Barney .
Get in there , and be quiet .
- You just made it . - Again .
Billy , will you sign this petition ?
Yeah , sure . What 's it for ?
We 're trying to have Dorry 's pub declared a landmark .
Mrs. Deagle 's trying to take his lease away .
His , too , huh ?
Yeah , she says it 's a dive , a public nuisance .
That 's where my dad proposed to my mom , you know .
That 's where everybody 's dad proposed to their mom . Cross your " T. "
Thanks .
- Good morning , Mrs. Deagle . - What 's good about it ?
Oh .
Klutz !
Watch it , watch it , watch it !
Forty , 60 , 80 ...
Uh ...
Two hundred . Thank you .
- Mrs. Deagle ? - What ? What ? What ?
I just wanted you to let you know that Joe himself got another job ...
My husband , Joe Harris .
And I 've taken up some sewing on the side .
Mrs. Harris , what are you trying to tell me ?
I 'm afraid that neither of us will be paid for two weeks .
Couldn 't you get Mr. Corben to ...
Well , to just give us a little more time ?
Mrs. Harris ,
the bank and I have the same purpose in life ,
to make money .
Not to support a lot of deadbeats !
Mrs. Deagle , it 's Christmas !
Now , you know what to ask Santa for , don 't you ?
Mommy , I 'm hungry .
Yes , honey . So am I.
This is what 's left of my imported Bavarian snowman .
Your dog broke it this morning .
Oh .
I 'm terribly sorry .
Just tell me how much I owe you , I 'll be more than happy ...
I don 't want money .
I want your dog .
Barney ?
Give him to me .
I 'll take him to the kennel . They 'll put him to sleep .
It 'll be quick and painless , compared to what I could do to him .
What could you do ?
I 'll catch the beast myself .
Then he 'll get what he deserves .
A slow , painful death .
Maybe I 'll put him in my spin dryer on high heat .
That 'd do it , all right .
Barney ! Barney !
Barney , will you get off of her ?
My dear lady , are you all right ?
I have a very weak heart . I can 't stand a shock like that !
What is that dog doing in here ?
Peltzer , this is a bank , not a pet store !
- Very good , Gerald . - Thank you , Mr. Corben .
Barney wouldn 't have hurt you , Mrs. Deagle , honestly ...
Excuses , excuses . You 're just like your father .
I 've listened to his miserable excuses for ten years , the loser .
As for you , you mangy cur ,
I 'll get you ...
When you least expect it .
Oh , my heart ! Oh !
I must apologize for this most unusual ...
You putz .
Hmm . The old bat never looked better .
It 's great . You 're doing fine .
Thanks .
Hello , Gerald .
If it isn 't Captain Clip-on .
Hey , guess who almost applied for unemployment today ?
- I give up . - You .
But Mr. Corben had second thoughts .
He gets so sentimental about the holidays .
- Imagine that . - Yeah .
I would 've fired you in a second .
Merry Christmas to you , too .
Excuse me , Mr. Jones .
Hey , Peltzer .
Look , I 'm a junior vice president at 23 .
By the time I 'm 25 , I 'm gonna have Mr. Corben 's job .
By the time I 'm 30 , I 'll be a millionaire . Look at you .
You 're practically supporting your whole family .
The world 's changing , Peltzer .
You gotta change with it . You gotta be tough .
Tough , huh ? And no one 's tougher than you , Ger ?
Don 't call me that . My name 's Gerald .
Can I get you a drink ?
Uh , give me a vodka martini . Shake , don 't stir .
You 're working here ?
Yeah , weeknights , so , Dorry doesn 't have to pay an extra waitress .
Well , I think that 's great .
Yeah , that 's real swell , if you like working for nothing .
Two more rounds for the pool table , and they 're all on the house .
Okay .
Hey , Kate .
You haven 't seen my new apartment .
I haven 't seen your old apartment .
Come on , we 're talking cable . Can we have dinner tomorrow night ?
I 'm working .
Why don 't you tell Dorry you 're sick ?
He can 't dock your pay .
Billy , is that you ?
Yeah , Mom , it 's me .
I 'm in the kitchen !
- Merry Christmas ! - Merry Christmas !
Merry Christmas , George !
Merry Christmas , movie house !
Merry Christmas , emporium !
- Hi , Mom . - Hi , sweetie .
Do you need any help ?
Um ... Yeah , you could do the eggs .
- Okay . - Thanks .
Dad 's machines , they work so well the first couple of weeks , then ...
Use the sink .
Mom , is something wrong ?
No . No , it 's a sad movie .
- How was your day ? - It was fine .
Mom , come on , what is it ? What 's wrong ?
Mrs. Deagle called again this afternoon .
Let 's not talk about it right now . Okay ? Don 't say anything to Dad .
Fine with me .
Don we now our gay apparel
Fa la la la la la La la la
Hi , sweetheart .
- Welcome home . - Hey , Dad .
Oh , I 'm glad you 're back . How was the trip ?
- It was great . - Yeah ?
Yeah . The Miracle Company , the people who have the Kitchen Companion ,
they just might be interested in the Bathroom Buddy .
Oh , great .
- Oh , thanks , Dad . - You 're gonna like this .
What is it ? A birdcage ?
No , no , no , don 't shake it . You 're gonna have to open it now .
It won 't wait till Christmas .
It 's a puppy , isn 't it ?
Yeah , it is . I can tell .
It 's a new car .
Oh , honey , would you dim the lights , please ?
Sure .
Dim the lights ? Dad , what , does it glow in the dark ?
It 's important . Trust me .
Go ahead , open it .
- What is it ? - No .
It 's your new pet .
Come on , Barney . Be a good dog .
You 're kidding .
Dad , it 's really neat .
Where 'd you get this ?
Oh , some little junk store in Chinatown .
- Can I pick him up , Dad ? - Sure , go ahead . Just be careful .
- You gotta be gentle . - I will .
I hope he 's housebroken .
Hey .
Oh , isn 't he cute ?
Has it got a name , Dad ?
Yeah , Mogwai .
- What ? - Mogwai .
- Mogwai ! - I don 't know . Some Chinese word .
I just call him " Gizmo . " He seems to like it .
Okay .
Gizmo .
Look up here a minute .
Hey . We 're getting our picture taken . Smile .
Ready ?
One , two , three ...
- No , no . - Bright light ! Bright light !
What happened ?
He hates bright lights .
There 's some things I forgot to tell you guys ,
and they 're really important .
Number one , he hates bright lights . We know that .
But you gotta keep him out of the sunlight .
Sunlight will kill him .
Number two , keep him away from water .
Don 't give him any water to drink . Whatever you do , don 't give him a bath .
And probably the most important thing ,
don 't ever feed him after midnight .
Gizmo .
Shh .
Uh-oh .
Looks like you hurt yourself .
Light bright ! Light bright !
Just sit down there and don 't fall off , okay ?
I 'll get you fixed up in no time .
All right .
Hold still .
Sorry . Sorry .
Try not to move so much , okay ?
Good night , Giz . I 'll see you in the morning .
Hello .
Mrs. Peltzer ?
I got a tree .
Oh , Christ .
Billy !
Hey , Billy .
I just brought in your Christmas tree .
What happened ?
Slight problem with the Peltzer Peeler-Juicer .
I thought your dad fixed it .
I thought so , too .
You know , you should just buy orange juice in cartons .
It 's a lot easier .
See , it works .
- I had to come . - So I see .
Now , I can see . It takes a certain kind of guy .
And that guy needs a certain kind of dame .
It 's no problem , Pete . You can leave it up here .
What are you gonna tell him ?
I 'll just tell him a bunch of bikers stole it from me on my way home .
Wow . The Hooded Menace . Issue number one .
It 's pretty neat , huh ?
Yeah . Where 'd you get it ?
Oh , Dr. Fantasy 's , I think .
- What 's that ? - Come here . I 'll show you .
This is my new pet . My dad gave him to me .
Neat . What 's his name ?
His name 's Gizmo . Hi , Giz .
- He 's a mogwai . - Mogwai !
Gizmo .
Cute .
Blink your eyes .
Go like that . Can you do that , huh ? Go like that ?
Now , watch , Pete . Maybe he 'll sing .
Come on , Giz . Let 's go over to the table .
I 'll be careful .
There we go .
Gee , Billy , where can I get one of those ?
I don 't know . This is the only one I 've ever seen .
Can I hold him ?
Sure . I don 't see why not . He seems to like you .
Great . Thanks a lot .
Sorry .
What was in that jar ?
Nothing . Just water !
Why is he making that noise ?
What is it ?
I don 't know .
Is it alive ?
One , two , three , four , five new ones .
Now , can I have one ?
Oh , I don 't know , Pete .
Hey , look , that one 's got a cute stripe on its head .
Hi , cutie .
Isn 't that incredible , Pete ?
Yeah , great .
Now , I mean , don 't you think this is ... This is incredible !
Oh , it is neat .
I 'm serious . It 's neat .
Oh , Gizmo , what 's the matter ?
- No , no , no . - Hey , Dad ?
Dad ?
I really think there 's something I should tell you ...
Billy , look at this .
Now , you 're familiar with the Bathroom Buddy , right ?
- Uh-huh . - I have made an improvement .
Watch this .
Now , let 's say , you 're late for the big meeting .
It 's really important .
You 're on your way . You reach up . Ah . You forgot to shave .
Now , what 're you gonna do ? Under normal circumstances ,
you are in trouble .
But not if you have the Bathroom Buddy . Right ?
Watch this .
Voilà .
What do you think ?
Say , that 's pretty neat .
- Oh , what 's this button ... - No , don 't push that .
- Sorry , Dad . - It 's okay .
No , I 'm really sorry .
It 's not your fault . I 'm working on that .
I haven 't finished that . I 'm gonna get that tomorrow .
Dad , the reason I came up here
is ' cause there 's a problem with the mogwai .
Yeah , what 's that ?
Well , it multiplies with water .
What ?
Dad , do you see what I mean ?
I don 't believe it .
All that from water ? They got wet ?
Yeah , plain water .
It 's funny . The new ones aren 't like Gizmo .
The one with the stripes seems to be the leader .
- You know what ? - What ?
I 'll bet every kid in America would like to have one of these .
Hmm .
They might even replace the dog as the family pet .
Think about it .
" The Peltzer Pet . "
This could really be the big one .
Barn ?
Barney ?
Oh , man . That dog ...
Barney , who did this to you ?
Hold on , I 'll get you down . Stay still .
Poor dog . Another minute , and he would 've been a dog-sicle .
Look , all I know is that I 'm positive that I closed and locked the door .
Well , Dad , then how else did she get to him ?
Billy , we can 't point any fingers , not even at Mrs. Deagle .
Mom , she 's been threatening him for weeks .
You know she 'd love to get her hands on him .
I know , honey , but we don 't have any proof .
We can 't even find any footprints leading up to the house .
Billy , I 'm gonna take Barney to your grandmother 's .
I 'll take him there on the way to the convention ,
Christmas Eve , I 'll pick him up on the way home .
He 'll be here for Christmas . It 's gonna be all right .
I don 't think we can drink this .
Why not ?
What 's wrong with this ?
Hey , Billy . Is that a mogwai ?
Mogwai , yeah , I 'm gonna have Mr. Hanson check it out .
And all of a sudden , there were five new ones like this one .
Now , watch this .
Uh-oh .
Um ...
Can I keep one of these here , run some tests on him ?
Yeah . I think I can spare one .
Knock-knock .
This is some Christmas , Katie , I 'll tell you .
First the old bat closes up the factory , and now , it 's my goddamn plow .
Mr. Futterman , guess what ? It 's time to go home now .
- How about one more beer ? - No , it 's late .
One more beer , I 'll help you clean up this mess .
No , thanks , though . It 'll be okay .
- It 'll be okay . - It will not be okay .
How 'd you , how 'd you like to bring your plow in for a tune-up
and find it loaded with foreign parts . Huh ?
I mean , everything . Gaskets , pistons , spark plugs .
All of it 's foreign .
- Hey , Billy . - Hi .
- Going home ? - Oh . Oh , yeah .
Gremlins .
You gotta watch out for the foreigners
' cause they plant gremlins in their machinery .
The same gremlins brought down our planes in the big one .
- Big one ? - That 's right .
World War II .
Good old W-W-I-I .
You know , they 're still shipping them over here .
They put them in the cars , they put them the TV .
They put them in the stereos , and the radios you stick in your ears .
They put them in the watches .
We got little teeny gremlins from their watches ...
I don 't think it 's such a good idea that you drive . Why don 't you walk home ?
You know , Katie , I think maybe I 'll walk home .
- Good . - It 's a nice night .
- Good night , kids . - Good night .
Ah .
Gremlins .
Silent night
Holy night
All is calm
All is bright
Round yon Virgin
Mother and Child
Holy infant ...
That was really good , you know , the way you handled Mr. Futterman .
Oh , I 'm used to it .
He 's been like that ever since he lost his job .
He 's like a lot of people around here . He just wants somebody to listen .
Especially around the holidays .
Why is that ?
It 's when a lot of people get really depressed .
Oh .
That 's funny , you know ,
because I always thought everyone was happy during the holidays ,
no matter what .
Well , most people are , but some aren 't .
While everybody else is opening their presents ,
they 're opening up their wrists .
Cheery thought .
It 's true . The suicide rate 's always the highest around the holidays .
Now I 'm depressed . Do you ever get depressed on Christmas ?
I don 't celebrate Christmas .
What , are you Hindu , or something ?
No , I just don 't like to .
What 's not to like ? I mean , it 's a lot of fun .
God !
Say you hate Washington 's Birthday or Thanksgiving , and nobody cares .
But say you hate Christmas ,
everybody makes you feel like you 're a leper or something .
- I 'm sorry . - No , it 's okay .
I 'm sorry . I 'm just a little tired and cranky .
Yeah .
Well ...
Thanks for walking me home , Billy .
Hey , no problem .
- Good night . - Good night .
Uh , Kate ?
Um ...
I was just wondering , uh , do you get any free nights off from Dorry 's ?
Thursdays .
Thursdays , yeah .
Because , I mean , I was just wondering , uh ,
if you 're not doing anything this Thursday night ,
maybe you 'd like to , uh , go out on a date
with me ?
I 'd love to .
Oh , yeah ?
Well , that 's great .
Yeah , well , we can talk about it , you know , on the phone and kind of
square everything away .
Good night , Billy .
' Night .
Hey there .
Give me your arm , boy . Come here , come on .
Give me your arm . No , no , this is not gonna hurt .
This isn 't gonna hurt .
Not a big guy like you . Come on .
There you go . See , that 's not so bad . Come on .
Good , good . That 's good . Okay .
Just a little blood test , pal . You 'll never miss it .
They 're like huge seed pods .
This must be the way that body in my closet was formed .
Miles , where did they come from ?
- Having fun ? - Fun .
- Pretty neat , huh ? - Neat .
What is with you guys ? How about shutting up for a change , okay ?
I already fed you .
Well , it 's not twelve o 'clock yet .
All right . Keep an eye on them , Giz . I 'll be back in a second .
Here we go .
Now , maybe , you guys will be quiet .
Hey , you guys are really hungry .
Hey , Giz , you want some ?
Do you want some chicken ?
No ?
All right .
Yum-yum .
That 's it , good buddy . Call it a night .
You fools , you 're in danger !
Can 't you see ? They 're after you !
They 're after all of us ! Our wives , our children , everyone !
They 're here already ! You 're next !
You 're next . You 're next ! You 're next !
You 're next !
Uh-oh !
- Mom ? - Yeah ?
Mom , could you come up here , please ?
Then I want you to bring the vacuum cleaner upstairs for me .
What are they ?
Well , they 're the mogwai , I guess . Except for Gizmo .
Did you get them wet , or something ?
No .
Did you feed them after midnight ?
Well , I gave them some chicken . But I made sure that it ...
No , no , no . Wait a minute .
I made sure ...
Mom ? What 's going on here ?
Mogwai ...
Yuck !
What 'd you say this was called ? A " putrid stage " ?
Pupal . Pupal stage .
- Like a butterfly . - Yeah , right .
Right . This is a cocoon , and inside , he 's going through changes .
Lots of changes .
Like my mother .
No . No , that 's different .
This is called a metamorphosis .
It 's a change in form , and in appearance .
Hello ?
Hello ? Hi , honey .
No , I 'm sure it works fine .
I was just out on the back porch for a second .
The convention 's great .
Yeah .
I said ... I said , it 's great .
Actually , the competition 's , uh ...
Sorry , miss .
The competition 's a little more advanced than I expected .
I was giving myself an oil ...
Some really neat things .
Oh , Rand .
You 've never been so far away on Christmas Eve before .
I know it 's Christmas Eve .
I 'll do the best I can .
All right . Bye-bye .
All I could get for it was $ 36 . It was their wedding ring ...
If there 's anything I can do ... But it 's completely out of my hands .
- Excuse me . - I 'll be absolutely delighted ...
- Hello , Mrs. Harris . - Hello , Gerald .
- I 'm under such terrible pressure . - Mr. Corben , don 't you ...
Why don 't you just speak to Mrs. Deagle about it ?
- If you just speak to her about it . - Speak to Mrs. Deagle ?
- Maybe ... - See , I could ...
Mrs. Deagle !
Deposit this to my account .
Where 's that psychotic canine of yours ?
Still hiding under the counter ?
Uh , no , I 'm afraid he 's on vacation .
You 'd better keep him behind locked doors , because if I catch him ,
he 's in for a slow death .
Here 's Mr. Bird 's heart .
Small animals lose heat faster than large ones .
So their blood must circulate faster to keep their bodies warm .
Now , in small birds ,
their hearts beat about 600 times per minute .
Cats , 130 .
Man , about 75 ,
and a big old elephant 's heart , only 25 a minute .
Hey , Doc , you got a human heart ?
Has he got a human heart ? Wait till you see this . Roll 10 .
Okay , class . Merry Christmas . Merry Christmas .
And , uh , if any of you wanna bring me a Christmas present ,
- uh , a cassette deck wouldn 't be bad . - Mr. Hanson ?
I just want to find out something ...
Of course , tickets to the Super Bowl would be very nice . Or a Rolls-Royce ...
Mr. Hanson , wait . Let me just talk to you for a second .
- Mr. Hanson ? - ... make it red .
Bye .
... this seat of love and compassion
weights only about three-fourths of a pound .
Yet the work it turns out is almost incredible .
How long would you say that it takes your heart to pump a quart of blood ?
Just standing around like this ?
A quart , a couple of minutes , I guess .
You 're way off .
Normally , the heart with pump a quart of blood in just about ten seconds .
In ten minutes , it would fill the gas tank of your car .
And it ten hours , it would fill a gas truck .
Billy ...
It just hatched .
I 'll be right there .
Uh ...
Hey there .
You , uh , remember me ?
Roy .
Huh ?
Remember me , don 't you ?
I , uh , went and got you ...
a candy bar .
I thought you might be hungry .
You hungry ?
Hmm ?
You should try one of these .
They , uh ...
Hey . Hey .
Hey there . Uh ...
Come here . Don 't , don 't be afraid . There 's no reason to be afraid .
Where 'd you go ? Huh ?
Where are you ? I know you 're in there .
I know you 're under there .
Come on , now .
Hey . You 're not still angry about that little blood test , are you ?
Come on out . Take a bite . Let me see you . Hmm ?
I just wanna , just wanna see you .
Here ... Here , you ...
You try some of this , now . I know you gotta be hungry .
Hmm ?
Yum-yum .
Hey .
There now . Don 't you feel better ?
Mr. Hanson ?
Ow !
Oh , yum .
Gizmo !
Yes , Billy , are you okay ? Where are you ?
Mom , they hatched . Get out of the house .
Phone home .
Mom ? Mom ?
Billy , what ...
Yummy-yum .
Yum-yum-yum .
Get out of my kitchen !
Neat .
Aah .
Hey !
- Mom , are you all right ? - I think so .
Mom , it 's Stripe .
- Should I get it ? - Yeah , go ahead and get it , honey .
Oh , I didn 't mean that .
Hello , Dr. Molinaro . Can we come in , please ?
My mom 's had a bit of an accident .
Billy . Be careful .
What happened ?
Giz ?
Hey . Oh , sorry .
Bright light . Bright light .
Come here .
They almost got you , huh ? Climb in here .
The question is totally without meaning .
Pardon me , sir . Stuff .
Thick and heavy .
Would 60 gallons be sufficient ?
I rarely use it myself , sir . It promotes rust .
Don 't worry , Giz , we 'll find him .
No !
Gremlins , huh ?
- Little monsters . - Right .
- Hundreds of them ? - Well , I 'm not sure . Maybe thousands .
Thousands .
Look , I know it sounds crazy . I know it does .
But in a matter of hours ,
this town 's gonna be turned into a major disaster area .
Now , you 've got to warn people !
- You think this kid is drunk , Brent ? - No , but you are .
I am not drunk !
Tell me something , Billy . Where do these little gremlins come from , huh ?
All right .
- My father gave me one as a present . - Oh , Christ .
Does your father always give you vicious little monsters for a present ?
No . No , they don 't start out vicious at first .
Oh , of course , not .
They don 't . They look like this .
Could you dim the lights in here , please ?
Sure .
Go ahead , Brent . Dim the lights .
Gusto .
' Tis the season to be jolly
Fa la la la la
Right , Murray ?
La la la
Sheila , will you quit messing with the TV ?
- You have the thingy . - Huh ?
Oh .
- Goddamn foreign TV . - Oh , now ...
I told you we should 've got a Zenith .
Foreigners .
I can 't get a damn thing on this .
Where are you going ?
I 'm gonna check the antenna . Maybe the damn thing blew down .
Be careful , dear .
What the hell is that ?
Aah !
Run ! Run , Sheila !
Make it go away !
- It 's them ! - Murray , you 're crazy .
There 's a real gremlin in my cab .
Yum-yum .
Oh . Hello , Anderson . Wanna mail something , do you ?
Yeah . Just a last-minute package , Father .
Be my guest .
That 's strange .
Patriotic little fellow , ain 't he ?
Waving the flag and everything .
Hey , there . Coochie-coochie ...
Be careful , Frank . He might tear your arm off .
You want me to put the cuffs on him ?
Billy , tell me something , will you ?
How come a cute guy like this
can turn into a thousand ugly monsters , huh ?
Well , you see , this is before it enters the pupal stage .
The pupal stage .
Yeah , right . Plus , it multiplies with water .
Oh , Christ .
Hey , get the kid some water , will you ?
I wouldn 't do that , Sheriff .
Sheriff 's office .
Yeah , speaking .
What ?
Oh , no .
Yeah , yeah , sure , sure , we ... We 'll be right over .
What happened ?
The Futtermans .
Something about a snowplow . A freak accident .
- It 's the creatures ! - Oh , the creatures .
The creatures are making it look like an accident .
Sheriff .
Sheriff , will you listen to me ?
You listen to me , kid .
Go on home , take little Gizmo there ,
sit by the fireplace and open your Christmas presents , okay ?
Attaboy .
- Let me drive . - No , you 're drunk .
You always get to drive .
Because I 'm the sheriff , asshole .
Deagle , Deagle , Deagle !
Kopeck , you stop that , you bad kitty .
Kopeck 's a bad kitty .
Ruble 's a good little kitty .
We 'll find you something to eat . She 's a good kitty .
Here we go . Here we go . Come on .
All right , you stop that .
You stop it .
Oh . Oh .
Mean kitty , you start eating before everybody gets here .
Come on , Dollar Bill .
Yes , here we go , Dollar Bill .
Mommy 'll fix you something good to eat here .
Everybody here ?
All right , let go of Mommy 's coat .
Here .
Christmas carolers .
I hate Christmas carolers .
Screechy-voiced little glue-sniffers .
I warned you brats .
Oh , what are they ? What are they ?
They 're here !
Oh , they 've come for me ! They 've come !
I 'm not ready .
I 'm not ready yet . I 'm not ready .
My God , Frye ! That was Mrs. Deagle .
Get them off ! Get them off ! Help me !
Help me !
Jesus , Frank . That 's Dave Meyers . He does Santa every year .
Get ' em off of me ! Get ' em off of me !
Yeah .
What the hell is he doing now ?
What 's that stuff he 's got all over him ?
Huh ?
Frank , I really think we should go now , okay ?
Start the car , ' cause I 'd really like to go back to the station now .
Frank , please .
Frank . Frank . Frank .
Frank !
Jesus , Frank .
What the hell are those things ?
It 's supposed to be Christmas . What the hell 's going on ?
- Shut up , will you ? - Frank !
- Frank ! - The brakes ! The brakes !
I don 't believe it .
You 're on with Rockin ' Ricky ! Go .
Hi , Rockin ' Ricky . My name 's Pete .
There 's these little green guys with big teeth
running around town wrecking things .
Hey , kid . This is Christmas , not Halloween .
Listen , gang .
Rockin ' Ricky 's getting fed up with this Orson Welles crap !
So , cool . Will ya ?
What 's that ? Kitty , what 's that back there ?
Some of Rockin ' Ricky fans ?
Hey ! You 're not a Rockin ' Ricky fan .
Sir , I notice that you 're a smoker .
Hmm ?
I said , I notice that you 're a smoker . I see the cigarettes .
I noticed , here , this broken ashtray .
Well , it 's very fortunate that I happened to come by right now .
Let me introduce myself . My name 's Randall Peltzer . I 'm an inventor .
" Fantastic Ideas for a Fantastic World . " I make the illogical logical .
And I have something here that I think you might be interested in .
Yes , sir , I do .
This is
the Peltzer Smokeless Ashtray .
I think this can solve your problem here , sir .
Please don 't bite me .
Wait a minute .
Aah !
Aah ! Okay .
Okay , okay .
- You all right ? - Yes .
Let 's get out of here .
Aah !
What 's that ? Aah !
Don 't worry . He 's with me . He 's not one of them .
What 's wrong ? Why isn 't the car starting ?
All right . We 're gonna have to make a run for it , okay ?
One , two , three !
They 've been here , too .
Billy , what are these things ? Where do they come from ?
They 're gremlins , Kate .
Just like Mr. Futterman said .
Now , I have another reason to hate Christmas .
What are you talking about ?
The worst thing that ever happened to me was on Christmas .
Oh , God . It was so horrible .
It was Christmas Eve .
I was nine years old .
Me and Mom were decorating the tree ,
waiting for Dad to come home from work .
A couple hours went by . Dad wasn 't home .
So , Mom called the office . No answer .
Christmas Day came and went , and still nothing .
So , the police began a search .
Four or five days went by .
Neither one of us could eat or sleep .
Everything was falling apart .
It was snowing outside .
The house was freezing , so I went to try to light up the fire .
And that 's when I noticed the smell .
The firemen came and broke through the chimney top .
And me and Mom were expecting them to pull out a dead cat or a bird .
And instead , they pulled out my father .
He was dressed in a Santa Claus suit .
He 'd been climbing down the chimney on Christmas Eve ,
his arms loaded with presents .
He was gonna surprise us .
He slipped and broke his neck . He died instantly .
And that 's how I found out there was no Santa Claus .
Don 't worry about that smoke . It 'll stop . It 's guaranteed .
Barney , shut up .
Don 't start with me . I got a long way to go .
Shut up .
Where did they all go ?
It 'll be light soon .
I bet they 're all together some place dark .
Mogwai !
Shh , Gizmo .
They 're inside .
All of them ?
Milk Duds .
What are they doing ?
They 're watching Snow White .
And they love it .
Where 's the boiler room ?
It 's in the back of the theater . Come on .
Down there .
Milk Duds .
Yum .
Ah .
Yum-yum .
Cover your mouth . Don 't breathe any gas .
Uh-oh .
- Billy . - Go .
Billy !
- Hurry up . - Move , Katie ! Watch out !
Come on !
Billy ... In the department store .
Oh , Stripe .
Gizmo !
That 's Stripe . He 's the leader .
If he gets to water , it 'll start all over again .
Take Giz , go back and try and find some kind of light switch .
Careful , Billy .
Billy !
... Ward is your snowplow headquarters .
Attention , Christmas shoppers .
Saturday morning at 8 : 30 , we 'll have Santa Claus for all the kiddies .
That 's right . Santa Claus ...
Don 't forget ... We have the Kingston Falls ...
Attention , Christmas shoppers .
Light bright .
Bye-bye , Billy !
... massive reports of the gremlins ...
It takes a certain kind of guy .
And that guy needs a certain kind of dame .
Glub glub .
Water !
Gun !
Hey , gang ! It 's been a rough night for Rockin ' Ricky ,
but he 's still on the air !
The Marines are standing by with fire hoses .
Barney ! Barney !
... we 're gonna turn the hoses on them !
Billy .
Move !
Gizmo !
Gizmo caca !
Light bright ! Light bright !
Light bright !
What the hell is that ?
Come here , Giz . You okay ?
Dad , your scarf ?
We switch now to a live report
from the scene of the Christmas Eve riots .
- We 're on ? - We 're on .
This is Lew Landers , WDHB 's Action Central News ,
at the site of Dorry 's Tavern ,
or what used to be Dorry 's Tavern , in Kingston Falls ,
where officials are now blaming
mass hysteria for the escalating series of unexplained
accidents , fires and explosions that rocked this once-peaceful town
on Christmas Eve .
The bizarre demise of Mrs. Ruby Deagle ,
widow of convicted stock-swindler Donald Deagle , seems to spell an end ...
Don 't chew that . Don 't chew .
I bet he 'd like some chicken soup .
Oh , honey , this is the gentleman who sold me the mogwai .
" Sold . " An interesting choice of words .
Papa !
Conflicting eyewitness reports concerning " little green men . "
You teach him to watch television ?
- I ... - Oh , no .
There was , I believe , a box .
Oh . Here . It 's here .
Dad ...
Rand , your scarf .
I warned you .
With mogwai comes much responsibility .
But you didn 't listen .
And you see what happens .
I didn 't mean it .
You do with mogwai what your society
has done with all of nature 's gifts .
You do not understand .
You are not ready .
- Papa ? - Yes ?
Uh ...
He has something to say to you .
You mean you understand what he says when he speaks to you ?
To hear , one has only to listen .
Bye , Billy .
Perhaps , someday , you may be ready .
Until then , mogwai
will be waiting .
Excuse me , sir .
Before you go , I just wanted to tell you
that I am truly sorry for what 's happened .
And , uh , if you would accept it , I 'd like to
give you this small token .
This is the only one . There 's one other one .
But this is an invention of mine .
Smokeless Ashtray .
How did you know that ?
Man at gas station tried to sell me .
Latest word in technology .
Very generous of you .
I 'm sure it will come in handy .
Bye-bye .
Well , that 's the story .
So , if your air conditioner goes on the fritz ,
or your washing machine blows up ,
or your video recorder conks out
before you call the repairman ,
turn on the lights , check all the closets and cupboards ,
look under all the beds .
Because you never can tell .
There just might be a gremlin in your house .